Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
The White Base and M'Quve's fleet
are now at a standstill...
...as they hide in the floating debris
of the Texas zone...
... unable to confirm
each others precise location.
Char and Sayla
Who is it? Who's watching me?
Thank you, Captain.
Don't mention it.
You're no ordinary soldier, Lalah.
Luck's on our side.
The air is escaping more slowly now.
Hurry and get back to the Zanzibar!
Yes, Captain.
I'll stay behind and stall the Gundam.
Right. But, Captain...
Lalah!
I keep telling you
there's no need to worry about me.
Now hurry and get out of here.
Char, the Red Comet... I believe in you.
I'm concerned about Amuro too, but...
... in this situation, the one who moves first
is at a disadvantage.
Mirai. What do you think?
I agree.
Amuro will be fine.
He's still alive.
How can you say that?
Well... I just know, somehow.
Amuro...
Captain Dellamin!
We have a clear advantage
in fighting strength. Let's attack!
No. We're only up against one enemy,
but it is a large warship.
If we carelessly revealed ourselves now...
But the Baromel has been attacked!
Lieutenant Uragang!
Captain...
Didn't you learn anything
while serving under Captain M'Quve?
Captain Barom's ship
will be here very soon.
We'll wait until then.
Yes, sir.
That's strange. The other mobile suit...
...I can't find it.
That was careless of me.
That was a red mobile suit,
so the pilot could've been Char.
A car?
That car...
Lalah...?
Found you, Gundam.
It's Lalah! I'm sure of it!
Was Char attacking me from the rear?
Or was that a different enemy?!
This might be getting complicated.
The Gundam's pilot
may be a Newtype as well.
I'll check one more time.
It seems there's no mistake.
My firing was accurate.
But he dodged every shot...
Coming from the side?!
This time from the front!
You're good, Char!
Where's Char?
Where's he coming from?
All right...just watch!
Char. I can read your moves.
What?!
Oh no!
C'mon, you've gotta respond a little faster...!
Char...!
I should've broken this thing in first.
I won't let you escape!
I've used up a lot of energy... Huh?
I almost had him, too...!
Did that get him?
But would Char really...?
It's badly damaged.
I seriously doubt that pilot
fell for a dummy explosion.
Aren't we able to get in touch
with the White Base yet?
Sir. The area has a high Minovsky particle
density, and with all the floating debris...
I know all that.
But we still must...
Wait. Just a moment, sir.
Is it the White Base?!
It's a Zeon high-speed heavy cruiser!
Direction 08-32. Relative velocity, 0078.
Right. Point us toward the enemy ship!
Prepare to open fire!
There's a vessel approaching us, sir.
What?!
A Federation Magellan-class battleship!
Right! Prepare for battle!
Rotate main cannons!
Lights from possible combat
detected at points A-17, B-33.
They're on Captain Barom's flight course.
Captain. Could it be Barom...?
Yes. We have no choice.
All vessels! Abandon your present positions!
Proceed to specified coordinates!
We've detected the enemy fleet, sir.
Heading for the unconfirmed battle zone.
So they got impatient...
Sayla! Launch the G-Fighter.
Job John, stand by in the Guncannon!
White Base, proceed!
Yes, sir.
We're entering fleet combat!
G-Fighter, launching!
The Trojan Horse is coming from behind us!
No one panic! Fire all guns!
I have you now.
Are they attacking with only one fighter?!
Mega particle cannons!
Main cannons! Missiles! Fire!
Large number of missiles incoming!
What about the anti-missiles?!
W-We don't have time!
We did it.
Almost too easy...
I see.
But, it's frightening to see what happens
when the momentum has shifted.
Th-They got us...
Good. Turnabout 180 degrees.
We'll approach the White Base.
One vessel advancing from
the unconfirmed battle zone.
Zeon?
Oh, just a moment! We have it!
It looks like a Magellan-class.
Magellan...?
Lieutenant Bright.
There might be enemy survivors inside.
Be cautious. I'll wait outside.
The White Base...
It's gotten a lot tougher.
Marker. Where did you detect the explosion?
Right, sir! Around Point N-5 in the C-Block.
Proceeding to N-5.
Omur! Sayla! Job! Stand by on the buggies.
Commencing descent.
Mobile Suit
Gundam
Touchdown completed.
All right. Omur! Sayla! Job!
Go out and search.
Go to level 2 battle stations
until we find Amuro.
Have Kai standby in the Guncannon...
Fraw. What's the status of the radio comm?
Fraw! What's the status of the radio comm?!
Huh? Yes, it should be okay to use!
Job John here!
Job John here! Come in, White Base!
Oh! Yes! White Base here, go ahead!
I haven't located the Gundam yet.
Roger.
Mr. Bright!
Copy that.
Fraw, could you go see how Hayato's doing?
He must be lonely.
But...
Fraw. Have Vammas come up here quickly.
Yes, sir.
I understand.
Everyone's so exhausted.
Sayla here. Sayla here.
Go ahead, White Base.
Sayla?
Oh? That's not Fraw Bow.
Yeah, I just relieved her.
Well? Have you found anything yet?
No. I'll keep looking.
B-Brother...
I thought I told you to quit the military.
And now you've become a Petty Officer...
Look who's talking, brother.
Joining the Zeon military
to take revenge on the Zabi family.
Your actions don't make any sense!
Do you truly believe that your own brother
is such a petty man, Artesia?
Huh?
Who...Who is she talking to?
That voice...?
The things Jimba Ral told us
might have been true after all.
The old man always used to say...
Why did your father, Lord Zeon,
create the Republic of Zeon?
He did it for the the future of all mankind...
...who are destined
to be reborn as Newtypes.
But he suddenly fell ill...
...and on his deathbed...
...your father singled out Degwin Zabi.
You wish someone like me
to be the next prime minister?
I understood Lord Zeon's
temperament very well.
He pointed out Degwin...
... to let us know that it was Degwin
who'd assassinated him.
Why else would your father's allies
have died, one after another?
And that's why I had no choice but
to raise you two, Casval and Artesia...
...on Earth under false identities.
The reason why I entered Zeon, and went
from high school to military academy...
...was so I could get close to the Zabi family.
But Artesia...
I've grown up a little since that time.
I realized that even if
the Federation defeats the Zabi family...
... humanity won't achieve true peace.
Why...?
Newtypes have appeared.
You mean because Amuro's a Newtype?
Newtype?!
Well.
I'm not pleased that a Newtype
has become my enemy.
From now on, I'll have to fight any way I can.
Jimba Ral taught us that Newtypes...
...are the ideal towards which
the entire human race should strive.
In which case, there should be no need
to make Newtypes your enemy!
Casval!
Brother, what are you thinking?!
I told you, I'll fight any way I can...
Artesia, you must leave the Trojan Horse!
Trojan Horse?! You mean the White Base?
Yes. I'll leave you enough gold
to pay your way from here to Earth...
Go to Earth and live out your life!
I'm no longer the brother you once knew.
B-Brother...
You must know why I wear this mask...
It's because I've discarded my past.
Brother!
Artesia...
Let me see your face one more time.
Please reconsider... my dear brother!
You're beautiful, Artesia.
War doesn't suit you.
Leave the Trojan Horse!
Brother!
Casval, my brother!
Bright! What's the matter, Bright?!
Is Amuro...?
No, it's nothing at all.
The static was awful.
Really...
Uh, yeah. But I am worried about Amuro.
Casval, my brother!
Br... Brother...!
No good. They've all been burned out...
This one, too.
Huh?
What is it?
I've never seen a machine like that.
It's a White Base buggy!
Hey! I'm up here!
Huh? That's Amuro!
Mr. Bright!
Ms. Sayla has found Amuro.
It can't move, so we'll need the Gunperry...
Right! Send it out immediately!
Hey...
What is it?
Transmission from Wakkein.
A Zanzibar-class warship is leaving...
...from the port on the other side of Texas.
What?!
Cancel the Gunperry launch.
We'll go in the White Base and pick up
the Gundam, Omur and the others.
Just one Magellan-class ship!
We'll break through it!
Captain. What exactly happened
while you were in Texas?
Lalah... Even my life has
its share of tragedies.
Please don't ask.
I understand.
Thanks to you, we've been able
to retrieve my Gelgoog.
Sorry about that.
It's just one enemy ship! Aim carefully!
The White Base will be here soon to help us.
We must hold our ground until then!
Okay, Mirai, take off!
Depart from the same port as the Zanzibar
and begin pursuit!
We've detected a signal-emitting
object near Shutter No. 3.
Is it an explosive?!
I don't know. But it's very small.
Why?! At a desperate time like this...!
Have Omur check it out!
Bright! Doesn't look like it's an explosive!
It's just trash!
Commandant Wakkein!
Th-That bastard Char...
W-We were too late!
Commandant Wakkein...
All I know is that the letter attached
to the case is addressed to you, Sayla.
Ditto for Omur.
Any idea who it's from?
Yes.
I have the right to inspect this...
But I'd rather you told me the contents
of the case, and who sent it to you.
I believe that the case is filled with gold.
You're quite sure of that?
Almost positive.
And who sent it?
Char Aznable, the Red Comet.
That's ridiculous!
I hope with all my heart
that you'll fulfill your promise.
To the gentle Artesia Som Deikun...
...With love, from Casval Rem Deikun.
My brother...
Dear brother Casval...
Sayla...or rather, Artesia...
...felt that as long as she could remember...
...she had followed her brother's back
always calling out his name.
When he was there beside her.
And when he wasn't.
Would she never again be able to call him...
her brother Casval?
Before anyone knows it...
...the war enters a new stage.
The phantom attacks
of one single mobile armor...
...confuse Amuro,
causing the Gundam's functions to falter.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
The Newtype: Challia Bull.
Next Time
The Newtype: Challia Bull
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...